<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jesse Crow</title>
    <description>Portfolio site for Austin-based designer, Jesse Crow.
</description>
    <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 20:06:43 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 20:06:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meeting My Design Hero</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was a great day because I got to meet my design hero, &lt;a href=&quot;http://draplin.com/&quot;&gt;Aaron Draplin&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love Draplin’s work because it’s bold and timeless. It’s something to aspire to. My work isn’t all #thicklines like Draplin’s, but I want to make things that won’t fade as trends change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With encouragement from a dear friend and a rush of adrenalin, I walked up to Draplin while he was setting up the merch booth before his talk, introduced myself, and asked him if he had any advice for new designers. Highlights include: don’t move to Portland, do work you love, and people are going to try to make design not fun—avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got to sit front row for his talk with my teacher, Sam. It was hilarious and inspiring and so good to hear, especially as a new designer. Highlights from the talk include: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;show the things you love&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;it takes work to make good design&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;document your process&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;think about how much time we throw away and invent your life with that time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;you don&#39;t have to take the carrot&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;get out there and get dirty&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;there&#39;s beauty in restraint&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Illustrator won&#39;t teach you anything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all boils down to one thing: “work hard and love this shit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/draplin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;with my design hero, Aaron Draplin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/04/30/meeting-my-hero.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/04/30/meeting-my-hero.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Demo Day</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was Demo Day and the end of my Iron Yard experience. Demo Day (and being at The Iron Yard in general) went by in the blink of an eye and it all feels like a blur. I can’t believe it’s over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Demo Day was set up science fair style, meaning it was conversation based, not pitch based, which took a lot of the pressure off.  I was so excited to share my final project (which you can find &lt;a href=&quot;http://jessecrow.com/projects/nationalparks.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) and talk about all I learned. I’m also very thankful to have a supportive fella, friends, and former co-workers who all came by to see my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about my final projects with others and seeing it in the wild was such a rewarding experience. It’s my capstone project that I’ve worked on for 14-16 hours a day for almost two weeks, that I’ve poured my heart into, that is an extension of me and everything I know as a designer and developer. I’m proud of the work I’ve done and all that I’ve learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Demo Day wrapped up, my cohort, our plus ones, and the teachers and staff went out to eat pizza and drink beer (treat yo’self) and then I went to see Sleater-Kinney with one of my dear friends and classmates. I don’t know what’s going to happen next, but I’m so excited for what’s to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/demoday.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;my booth setup at demo day&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/04/18/demo-day.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/04/18/demo-day.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Designing For Myself</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the midst of final projects, our class also worked on our personal logos and business cards. Designing something for myself is one of the most challenging things I’ve done so far in this class. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve put so much additional (and probably unnecessary) pressure on myself for my logo to be perfect. Not just design wise, but I’ve also felt like it has to be the perfect representation of myself. This, coupled with just turning twenty-five a couple weeks ago, has led me to feel like I’m in the thick of a quarter life crisis. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by asking family, friends, and Sam what five words and a color they associate with me to get an idea as to how others perceive me. Then our class doing a timed logo challenge like we did earlier in the cohort. From there, I sketched and iterated ideas, brought them into Illustrator, and iterated and iterated and iterated and fussed with pen tool points until I was satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My two main concepts were a bird and a mason jar. I ultimately decided to go with the mason jar because it has more depth and goes past the obvious (my last name is Crow, afterall). We got our business cards today and I’m over the moon with how they turned out and still can’t believe I’m getting into a world where I get to have business cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/personal-logos-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mason jar and bird logo iterations&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/personal-logos-v2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mason jar and bird logo iterations&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/bizcards.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;business cards&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/04/10/personal-logo-design.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/04/10/personal-logo-design.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting Final Projects</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Y’all, somehow the time has flown by and I’m starting my final project. This is not a drill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m feeling excited and inspired and a little overwhelmed about just how much work I have to get done in the next two weeks. I know I’m capable and armed with a fantastic schedule to stick with, but sometimes the size and importance of this project gets the best of me. Mostly I’m trying to shush the thoughts of “you only have ___ days left here” that have become more frequent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my final project, I’m going to redesign the home page of the National Park Service website and four pages from Great Smoky Mountains National Park’s website. So far I’ve done my research, created a word list, done brand/reputation, competitor, and SWOT analyses, considered the audience, come up with a list of potential concepts, and done sketches based on the strongest three concepts. Seems like a lot (and it is), but it’s only a small drop compared to what’s to come. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just need to keep in mind this mantra from Leslie Knope:
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/doit.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Inspirational Leslie Knope gif&quot; class=&quot;blog-gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/04/01/starting-final-projects.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/04/01/starting-final-projects.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Front End &amp;amp; Rails Demo Day</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today the Front End and Rails classes had their demo day—I can’t believe 12 weeks has already gone by!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing a demo day first hand was a really awesome experience (and it helped calm my already happening jitters about my demo day in three weeks). It was set up science fair style, so everyone had a station set up with a big monitor displaying their final project, business cards, a name tag, etc. People could then move from station to station and I think there was a lot less pressure on the students since (at least from what I could see) presentations were very conversational. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so amazed and impressed with what my classmates and friends created in two weeks and how much they’ve learned in twelve! If they’re the future of engineering, it’s in &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; good hands.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/03/27/fee-and-ror-demo-day.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/03/27/fee-and-ror-demo-day.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On Rejection</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I turned twenty-five. Yesterday I also got a rejection letter from a conference I applied to speak at. Needless to say, I’m feeling a little blue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting rejected wasn’t something that crossed my mind when I applied. It’s not an arrogance thing; I know that I’m still so new in this world and that I have a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; left to learn. It’s because I don’t visualize rejection when trying to reach a goal. Why would I? When I think about my goals, I only visualize myself reaching them; I only want to put good, positive energy towards them. This is both a blessing and a curse. I’m great at staying positive, but when I do face rejection, it really hurts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was already crafting my talk (which I’m now pivoting into a blog post, so stay tuned!). I was picturing myself, a week after demo day, leaving the nest of The Iron Yard, giving a talk downtown, meeting new people, and taking the world by storm.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in a very similar position seven years ago when I turned eighteen. I got a rejection letter from UT, one of my top choice colleges. As an out of state applicant, I knew getting in was a long shot and actively tried not to get my hopes up. But I still pictured myself in the big city, learning things I didn’t even know I could learn about, going to a show every night, and eating lots of tacos. I was really upset, but it all worked out. I attended the tiny, liberal arts college of my dreams (Go Majors!), made some of the best friends I could ever hope to have, received an education unlike any other, and had incredible mentors. I also fell in love with the city, which meant I stuck around for a couple years after graduation, made even more fantastic friends, met my wonderful fella, and we rescued our two dogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rejection happens for a reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting rejected from speaking at a conference might not have the same life changing effect as choosing where to go to college, but there’s a reason. Maybe it’ll prepare me for rejection as I start my job search in a couple of weeks. Maybe I’ll get tickets to a private Bonnie Prince Billy show on the same day. Maybe I’ll &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; be napping and recovering from the twelve most intense weeks of my life. Who knows. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rejection isn’t the important part. How you handle rejection is what’s important. Rejection is awful and it can really drag you down-but you don’t have to let it. It’s okay to be sad for a little while, but then channel that sadness into something bigger and better. I’m not going to let this discourage me from putting myself out there. I’m only going to put myself out there more and dream bigger. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/03/25/on-rejection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/03/25/on-rejection.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Logo Challenge</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we spent class time talking about logos. We watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/113751583&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; video where the incredible &amp;amp; inspirational Aaron Draplin designs a logo in 15 minutes. Our take away was “see how much you can do if you don’t edit in your head and put every idea down?!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sam put that take away to the test with the most insane and fun logo challenge. We all cleared our desks of everything except for a pack of sticky notes and a Sharpie. Every 30 seconds Sam would say a new topic and we had to sketch as many ideas as we could. And we had a Sharpie, so we had to &lt;em&gt;commit&lt;/em&gt;. Topics included: SXSW, a library, tacos, water, Valentine’s Day (but no hearts allowed), beer, and email. We sketched for what seems like hours, but I think it was closer to thirty minutes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/logo-challenge1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;some of my logo sketches&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took a short break and then picked our five favorite sketches to bring into Illustrator. I chose an Austin dentist, a quilt conference, women in tech, the Oregon Trail, and a library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/logo-challenge-top5.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;top 5 logo sketches&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge wasn’t over when we moved into Illustrator. We had to create 10 different logos of each concept, and had to (try to) stick to 1 minute for each. I ended up spending about 3 minutes on each one, but I was able to move around Illustrator faster than I expected.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/logo-challenge-illustrator.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;working in illustrator&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a blast with this assignment. It very much felt like a summer camp activity and it was a really fun way to get comfortable with not editing in my head. I learned that putting down the obvious, just getting it out of my system, helps me move past it and onto better design. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/03/17/logo-challenge.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/03/17/logo-challenge.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Logos and Iteration</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The past couple of days, we’ve learned about logo design. We’ve spent time discussing what make a logo successful or unsuccessful and have jumped in to making a logo for our restaurant redesign project. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by revising the wordlist I created when we started the restaurant redesign project. I used my original list, but flushed it out more. From there, I created a morphological matrix. I based the categories of my morphological matrix on common themes in my wordlist. I then went back and color coded the categories with associated words. Using a morphological matrix is an awesome way to come up with new ideas and explore what happens when you put two different things together; it helps you move past the obvious.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/restaurant-wordlist.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;restaurant wordlist&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After creating the matrix, our assignment was to come up with fifty ideas for logos. FIFTY whole ideas?! At first I didn’t think it would be possible, but thanks to the matrix it wasn’t too hard to do. One thing I had to get over very quickly at this point in the process is my lack of drawing skills. I do great in general arts and crafts, but drawing has never been my strong suit. As it turns out, it doesn’t matter as long as I can get the point across. At this point in the process, I also felt very thankful for Illustrator.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/restaurant-firstlogos-1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Restaurant Logos, First Round&quot; class=&quot;post-float-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/restaurant-firstlogos-2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Restaurant Logos, First Round&quot; class=&quot;post-float-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we had a critique of the logos we created yesterday. Out of the fifty I made yesterday, seven of mine were chosen for iteration. Iteration is such an important part of designing a logo. Iteration helps you move past the obvious, explore ideas fully, and craft the best work possible. I came up with sixty new versions today and I’m much more proud of most of them than the fifty I created yesterday. I felt like I was getting to put all of my effort into the best concepts, and that’s a satisfying feeling. I have a couple of favorites that I want to pursue more, but I have to remember to not be married to a concept. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/restaurant-secondlogos-1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Restaurant Logos, First Round&quot; class=&quot;post-float-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/restaurant-secondlogos-2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Restaurant Logos, First Round&quot; class=&quot;post-float-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/03/10/on-iteration.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/03/10/on-iteration.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Restaurant Redesign</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re moving full steam ahead with our restaurant redesign projects! We’ve gotten a lot done since I last blogged about &lt;a href=&quot;http://crowjm.github.io/2015/02/22/exploring-typography.html&quot;&gt;it&lt;/a&gt;. Since we’ve hit the halfway point (!!!) we’re going to be working on at least one project a week for rest of the semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week and over the weekend, we had to take our projects from 3 sets of sketches of the menu section to 3 sets of wireframes, pick the final layout, create comps, and code a responsive site with two addition pages. It sounds like a ton of work (and it was), but we kept a steady pace. Breaking it into smaller assignments to accomplish each day made the project seem much less overwhelming. As my Mama says, “the best way to eat an elephant is one bite at a time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hit a rut when designing the home page. I felt like none of the ideas I tried matched the whacky and wonderful personality of the restaurant I’m working on. After looking at some ideas on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siteinspire.com/&quot;&gt;Site Inspire&lt;/a&gt;, I found one concept that worked: big and bold color blocks. I’m not sure if it’s the most effective way to present the information, but it’s a good starting point for iteration. If you’d like to see what I’ve created thus far, you can find it &lt;a href=&quot;http://crowjm.github.io/tiy_assignments/day_29/bouldin_redesign/index.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got feedback on our designs from our classmates and from Sam and will be revising soon. This week we’re jumping into the world of logo design and also working on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csszengarden.com/&quot;&gt;CSS Zen Garden&lt;/a&gt;. I’m excited to be working on two very different projects at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/03/08/restaurant-redesign.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/03/08/restaurant-redesign.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TIY Hackathon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today marked the end of the TIY Austin Hackathon. The past four days have been some of the most demanding and challenging yet. It was our first big project to design everything on our own (and our first group project). I can’t believe we’re finally at this point!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our hackathon started Thursday afternoon with idea pitches. I pitched a couple of ideas, but my favorite was for an app that would help you plan your garden. After pitches, the instructors picked the ideas that were realistic to get done in such a short amount of time. From there, we split into teams. Each team had one Ruby on Rails developer, one front end developer, and one designer (or front end student acting as designer). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My garden app idea (which one of my teammates, Drew, thought to call GreenThumb) ended up being what my team worked on and I was over the moon to bring it from concept to reality!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday afternoon was spent planning. I sketched out different layout ideas, made wireframes for the final version and worked on design research. I was feeling very stuck in terms of design. I could hear my instructor, Sam, saying “good design moves past the obvious” over and over in my head, but all I could think of were greens, yellows, blues, and garden beds. Too obvious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday morning, my teammate Alex and I pair programmed the html and basic framework for the app. It was refreshing to work with someone else and to be coding in a new environment (inside a Rails app structure, not just a regular, static html page). When we were done, I started thinking of design concepts again, and that’s when it hit me: Victory Garden posters! Historical references, creating a feeling of responsibility, patriotism, and pride, and beautiful color palettes to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the rest of Friday creating a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/crowjm/GreenThumb-Design-Planning/blob/master/GreenThumb_StyleTile.psd&quot;&gt;style tile&lt;/a&gt; and getting basic design done. Our apps had to be responsive, so I wanted to get the basic flow of elements done before I went too deep into the design elements. I was able to get most things wrapped up by Saturday afternoon and then I worked on the design. Saturday evening rolled around, and I just wasn’t happy with what I had done. It felt bland and lacking personality. I jumped into Photoshop and made a hero image to replace what was then green text on a blue background. I still felt like it wasn’t enough. So, I ventured into Illustrator and made some carrots (which I am SO proud of, y’all). I wasn’t sure how I was going to incorporate them, but I knew they were the missing piece. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;svg class=&quot;carrots&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; id=&quot;Layer_1&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot; x=&quot;0px&quot; y=&quot;0px&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 100 100&quot; enable-background=&quot;new 0 0 100 100&quot; xml:space=&quot;preserve&quot;&gt;
&lt;g id=&quot;XMLID_2_&quot;&gt;
	&lt;g&gt;
		&lt;path fill=&quot;#F59E42&quot; d=&quot;M43.9,85.8c0,0-0.1-8.3-0.1-18.2l1.5,0.4l2.1,0.3l1.1,0.3C46,78,43.9,85.8,43.9,85.8z&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;path fill=&quot;#F59E42&quot; d=&quot;M48.5,68.6l-1.1-0.3L45.3,68l-1.5-0.4c0-0.9,0-1.9,0-2.9l1.6,0.3l2.5,0l1.4,0.5
			C49.1,66.5,48.8,67.6,48.5,68.6z&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;path fill=&quot;#F59E42&quot; d=&quot;M43.8,64.7C43.9,51.2,44.1,35.9,45,34c1.6-3.5,8.8-1.9,10.6,1c1,1.6-2.7,17.1-6.2,30.5L47.9,65l-2.5,0
			L43.8,64.7z&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/g&gt;
	&lt;g&gt;
		&lt;path fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; d=&quot;M48.5,68.6C46,78,43.9,85.8,43.9,85.8s-0.1-8.3-0.1-18.2
			c0-0.9,0-1.9,0-2.9C43.9,51.2,44.1,35.9,45,34c1.6-3.5,8.8-1.9,10.6,1c1,1.6-2.7,17.1-6.2,30.5C49.1,66.5,48.8,67.6,48.5,68.6z&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;46.3&quot; y1=&quot;35.9&quot; x2=&quot;53.7&quot; y2=&quot;36.8&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;46.9&quot; y1=&quot;40&quot; x2=&quot;51.9&quot; y2=&quot;40.7&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;47.7&quot; y1=&quot;44.2&quot; x2=&quot;52.1&quot; y2=&quot;44.8&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;45.9&quot; y1=&quot;48.3&quot; x2=&quot;50.5&quot; y2=&quot;48.4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;46.4&quot; y1=&quot;52.4&quot; x2=&quot;50.3&quot; y2=&quot;52.9&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;45.6&quot; y1=&quot;55.8&quot; x2=&quot;48.8&quot; y2=&quot;56.3&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;45.5&quot; y1=&quot;59.9&quot; x2=&quot;48.2&quot; y2=&quot;60.2&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;45.4&quot; y1=&quot;65.1&quot; x2=&quot;47.9&quot; y2=&quot;65&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;46.2&quot; y1=&quot;63.1&quot; x2=&quot;48&quot; y2=&quot;63.2&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;45.3&quot; y1=&quot;68&quot; x2=&quot;47.4&quot; y2=&quot;68.3&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;45.1&quot; y1=&quot;71.3&quot; x2=&quot;46.9&quot; y2=&quot;71.3&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;45.2&quot; y1=&quot;74.1&quot; x2=&quot;45.7&quot; y2=&quot;73.9&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;44.5&quot; y1=&quot;76.6&quot; x2=&quot;45.4&quot; y2=&quot;76.7&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/g&gt;
&lt;/g&gt;
&lt;g id=&quot;XMLID_3_&quot;&gt;
	&lt;g&gt;
		&lt;path fill=&quot;#F59E42&quot; d=&quot;M30.4,82.1c0,0,1.4-8.2,3.2-18l1.4,0.7l2,0.7l1.1,0.5C33.9,74.9,30.4,82.1,30.4,82.1z&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;path fill=&quot;#F59E42&quot; d=&quot;M38.1,66L37,65.5l-2-0.7l-1.4-0.7c0.2-0.9,0.3-1.9,0.5-2.8l1.5,0.6l2.5,0.4l1.3,0.7
			C39,64.1,38.5,65.1,38.1,66z&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;path fill=&quot;#F59E42&quot; d=&quot;M34.1,61.4c2.5-13.3,5.5-28.3,6.7-30c2.2-3.2,9-0.3,10.3,2.8c0.7,1.8-5.8,16.3-11.6,28.9l-1.3-0.7L35.6,62
			L34.1,61.4z&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/g&gt;
	&lt;g&gt;
		&lt;path fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; d=&quot;M38.1,66c-4.2,8.9-7.7,16.1-7.7,16.1s1.4-8.2,3.2-18
			c0.2-0.9,0.3-1.9,0.5-2.8c2.5-13.3,5.5-28.3,6.7-30c2.2-3.2,9-0.3,10.3,2.8c0.7,1.8-5.8,16.3-11.6,28.9C39,64.1,38.5,65.1,38.1,66
			z&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;41.8&quot; y1=&quot;33.4&quot; x2=&quot;48.8&quot; y2=&quot;35.7&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;41.6&quot; y1=&quot;37.6&quot; x2=&quot;46.5&quot; y2=&quot;39.2&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;41.6&quot; y1=&quot;41.9&quot; x2=&quot;45.9&quot; y2=&quot;43.2&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;39.1&quot; y1=&quot;45.6&quot; x2=&quot;43.6&quot; y2=&quot;46.6&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;38.9&quot; y1=&quot;49.7&quot; x2=&quot;42.6&quot; y2=&quot;50.9&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;37.5&quot; y1=&quot;52.9&quot; x2=&quot;40.5&quot; y2=&quot;54&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;36.6&quot; y1=&quot;56.9&quot; x2=&quot;39.2&quot; y2=&quot;57.7&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;35.6&quot; y1=&quot;62&quot; x2=&quot;38.1&quot; y2=&quot;62.4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;36.8&quot; y1=&quot;60.2&quot; x2=&quot;38.5&quot; y2=&quot;60.6&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;35&quot; y1=&quot;64.8&quot; x2=&quot;37&quot; y2=&quot;65.5&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;34.2&quot; y1=&quot;68.1&quot; x2=&quot;36&quot; y2=&quot;68.4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;33.8&quot; y1=&quot;70.9&quot; x2=&quot;34.3&quot; y2=&quot;70.8&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;32.6&quot; y1=&quot;73.2&quot; x2=&quot;33.5&quot; y2=&quot;73.5&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/g&gt;
&lt;/g&gt;
&lt;g id=&quot;XMLID_1_&quot;&gt;
	&lt;g&gt;
		&lt;path fill=&quot;#F59E42&quot; d=&quot;M65.4,76.3c0,0-3-6.5-6.5-14.4l1.3-0.2l1.7-0.5l1-0.2C64.4,69.4,65.4,76.3,65.4,76.3z&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;path fill=&quot;#F59E42&quot; d=&quot;M63,61l-1,0.2l-1.7,0.5l-1.3,0.2c-0.3-0.7-0.7-1.5-1-2.3l1.4-0.3l2-0.9l1.3-0.1C62.7,59.2,62.9,60.1,63,61
			z&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;path fill=&quot;#F59E42&quot; d=&quot;M57.9,59.6C53.2,49,48,36.8,48,35c0-3.3,6.3-4.6,8.7-3c1.3,0.9,3.9,14.4,5.9,26.3l-1.3,0.1l-2,0.9
			L57.9,59.6z&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/g&gt;
	&lt;g&gt;
		&lt;path fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; d=&quot;M63,61c1.4,8.4,2.4,15.2,2.4,15.2s-3-6.5-6.5-14.4
			c-0.3-0.7-0.7-1.5-1-2.3C53.2,49,48,36.8,48,35c0-3.3,6.3-4.6,8.7-3c1.3,0.9,3.9,14.4,5.9,26.3C62.7,59.2,62.9,60.1,63,61z&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;49.8&quot; y1=&quot;36&quot; x2=&quot;55.9&quot; y2=&quot;34.2&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;51.7&quot; y1=&quot;39.1&quot; x2=&quot;55.9&quot; y2=&quot;37.8&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;53.8&quot; y1=&quot;42.1&quot; x2=&quot;57.5&quot; y2=&quot;41&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;53.8&quot; y1=&quot;45.9&quot; x2=&quot;57.5&quot; y2=&quot;44.4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;55.6&quot; y1=&quot;49&quot; x2=&quot;58.9&quot; y2=&quot;48&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;56.2&quot; y1=&quot;52&quot; x2=&quot;58.9&quot; y2=&quot;51.2&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;57.6&quot; y1=&quot;55.2&quot; x2=&quot;59.8&quot; y2=&quot;54.5&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;59.3&quot; y1=&quot;59.4&quot; x2=&quot;61.3&quot; y2=&quot;58.4&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;59.3&quot; y1=&quot;57.5&quot; x2=&quot;60.7&quot; y2=&quot;57&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;60.3&quot; y1=&quot;61.7&quot; x2=&quot;62&quot; y2=&quot;61.2&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;61.3&quot; y1=&quot;64.4&quot; x2=&quot;62.7&quot; y2=&quot;63.8&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;62.4&quot; y1=&quot;66.6&quot; x2=&quot;62.7&quot; y2=&quot;66.2&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;line fill=&quot;none&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; x1=&quot;62.7&quot; y1=&quot;68.8&quot; x2=&quot;63.4&quot; y2=&quot;68.6&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/g&gt;
&lt;/g&gt;
&lt;polyline fill=&quot;#A3AE79&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; points=&quot;45.2,30.9 47.1,19.4 48.8,20.4 46.8,30.9 &quot; /&gt;
&lt;polyline fill=&quot;#A3AE79&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; points=&quot;52.5,32.4 52.6,20.7 54.4,21.5 54.1,32.2 &quot; /&gt;
&lt;polyline fill=&quot;#A3AE79&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; points=&quot;46.1,28.3 41.2,24 42.5,22.5 45.7,27.2 40.6,17.9 
	42.5,17.9 45.8,25.9 43.3,15.2 44.8,15.2 46.7,24.9 &quot; /&gt;
&lt;polyline fill=&quot;#A3AE79&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; points=&quot;53.5,29.4 48.7,25.1 49.9,23.7 53.2,28.3 48,19.1 
	49.9,19.1 53.3,27 50.8,16.4 52.3,16.4 54.1,26.1 &quot; /&gt;
&lt;polyline fill=&quot;#A3AE79&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; points=&quot;49.4,33.4 46.8,27.4 48.6,26.7 49.6,32.2 48.8,21.7 
	50.5,22.5 50.2,31.1 52.4,20.4 53.7,21 51.4,30.6 &quot; /&gt;
&lt;polyline fill=&quot;#A3AE79&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; points=&quot;48.2,27 53.3,23.1 52.2,21.5 48.6,26 54.4,17.1 52.5,17 
	48.6,24.7 51.8,14.2 50.3,14.1 47.8,23.6 &quot; /&gt;
&lt;polyline fill=&quot;#A3AE79&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; points=&quot;45.9,23.9 51,20 49.9,18.4 46.3,22.9 52.1,14 50.2,13.8 
	46.3,21.6 49.5,11.1 48,11 45.5,20.5 &quot; /&gt;
&lt;polyline fill=&quot;#A3AE79&quot; stroke=&quot;#000000&quot; stroke-miterlimit=&quot;10&quot; points=&quot;54.4,30.9 59.5,27 58.3,25.5 54.8,29.9 60.5,21 
	58.6,20.9 54.8,28.6 57.9,18.1 56.5,18 54,27.6 &quot; /&gt;
&lt;/svg&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday afternoon I went to campus to meet with my teammates and get help from Sam with an nth-of-type issue I had. I was lucky enough to also get a design critique. Critiques used to terrify me, but I got over it after realizing how much of a valuable tool in the design process. People can steer you in the right direction if you get off track, point out things you might not realize, and/or let you know that you’re on the right path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning, we presented our projects. It was a relief and was so neat to see what everyone else had worked on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to check out GreenThumb, you can find it &lt;a href=&quot;https://greenthumbapp.herokuapp.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Some of the features are still in the works. I’ll be iterating the design in the coming weeks, so stay tuned for updates!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/03/02/TIY-Hackathon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/03/02/TIY-Hackathon.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
