<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jesse Crow</title>
    <description>Portfolio site for Austin-based designer, Jesse Crow.
</description>
    <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 15:38:12 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 15:38:12 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sketchnotes: Q&amp;amp;A With Ethan Marcotte</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I sat in on a Q&amp;amp;A session with &lt;a href=&quot;http://ethanmarcotte.com/&quot;&gt;Ethan Marcotte&lt;/a&gt; at The Iron Yard. Ethan is the creator of responsive web design(!), which is the methodology I learned to design websites. I feel very lucky to have been there and to learn first-hand from someone who’s had such an impact on web design. Thanks, Ethan!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/EM-10915-sketchnotes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sketchnotes from Ethan Marcotte&#39;s Q&amp;amp;A at The Iron Yard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/10/10/em-sketchnotes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/10/10/em-sketchnotes.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A New Adventure</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past month and a half, I’ve been searching for my next job, which has been an adventure in and of itself. One of the pieces of advice I heard over and over while in school was to not settle. I really took that to heart and wanted to make sure I found a job where I could consistenly contribute and be challenged and grow at a fantastic company.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exciting news: my search is over! I accepted an offer from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ibm.com/design/&quot;&gt;IBM Design&lt;/a&gt; and will start as a front end developer in January! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t wait to get started and am counting down the days until Design Camp! I’m also really looking forward to the transistion from design to development and to spend more time coding and programming (although I’ll still work on design-oriented side projects).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/09/21/a-new-adventure.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/09/21/a-new-adventure.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>100 Days Reflections: Part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m almost halfway done with my 100 Days challenge. Where has the time gone?! I’m more thankful that I’m doing this sort of challenge every day that passes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s some of what I’ve learned from this challenge so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;blog-list&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;It&#39;s much easier to make something when I have a clear plan of what I want to make (big surprise). I&#39;ve learned that if I don&#39;t have a clear plan of action, my designs end up all over the place and less successful than designs that I&#39;ve thought out. I&#39;m starting to hone in on that by having one theme that I work off of. Currently I&#39;m working on a series of Austin icons, focusing on using shapes and shading.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I need to have a notebook with me at all times to keep track of ideas, sketch, and practice lettering. On my desk, in my purse, on my bedside table.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;On days when I&#39;m exhausted and/or stressed, I&#39;m more likely to bake something than design something.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I do my best work in the morning, before the pups wake up. No distractions and not having anything else from the day to worry about means that I can focus better on the task at hand.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;There are ways to get out of a rut. Early in the challenge when I would get stumped, I would give myself a hard time. Now I look through my notebooks for ideas or pick a course to complete on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.skillshare.com/classes&quot;&gt;Skillshare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I have more fun working on something that pushes what I know, not projects that play it safe.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I stay more in my zone when listening to music. And the music is important! I&#39;ll share a playlist of what&#39;s been on heavy rotation on the blog soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/09/03/first-100-day-reflections.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/09/03/first-100-day-reflections.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>For Grandpa</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started my blog, I wanted its sole purpose to be documenting my journey as a designer. I was very adamant that I would keep my personal life out of it. But life shows up and the line between the two gets blurred and here we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love design because it creates order in chaos. I love design because good design mandates empathy and inclusiveness. And new to my list of reasons why I love design is that it’s a way to feel closer to people I’ve lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday marked six weeks since my Grandpa passed away. I’d been keeping busy, trying to not think about things, but lately I’ve started to unpack everything. I’ll have flashbacks to the call I got from my Dad telling me that if I wanted to see Grandpa I needed to come now. Back to the VA Hospital in Little Rock—the glow and noises of all the machines, the complete silence and eerie, unsettling feeling of the common areas of the hospital at 3am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we were sorting through belongings the weekend of the funeral, my Mama gave me two albums of photos that Grandpa took in the Blue Ridge Mountains. She told me she thought I would be able to use them and they are the absolute best thing I could have inherited. They’ve been tucked away until today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/blueridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photos of the Blue Ridge Mountains&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sorted through the photos and there was one that I kept going back to. I knew the perfect quote to go with it, so I lettered it, brought it into Illustrator and cleaned it up, and added it to the photo. It’s comforting to be able to make things with the photos and have a sense of connection. I’m excited for all the other projects I can use them in and to keep making, keep remembering. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/100days/day26-muir.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photos of the Blue Ridge Mountains with a John Muir quote&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/08/15/for-grandpa.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/08/15/for-grandpa.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>100 Days of Making</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There is so much that I want to learn and try and do and make. I have a running list of projects I want to start, skills I want to learn, meals I want to cook, etc. — and it’s extensive. Why aren’t I making something every day?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been making excuses. I’m too tired from work, I need to find the right tutorial, maybe once I’m better at Illustrator I can get into more illustration-heavy projects, and so on. Yesterday, when I sat down with Illustrator and made an illustrated portrait of one of my dogs (which I am so proud of, y’all), I realized all of these excuses are complete nonsense. So what if I’m tired? Make a cup of tea and go for a little walk. Who says I need a tutorial, I’ve got a brain and can figure this out! And spoiler alert, self, the only way I’m going to get better at anything is to do the thing, make the thing, pick up the tools and create and revise and create some more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a new designer is hard, but it’s not a reason to not try. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m feeling inspired and empowered, and I’m starting the 100 Days Project! You can read more about the 100 Days Project &lt;a href=&quot;https://thegreatdiscontent.com/100days&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I’m &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; excited to make and create and do and learn and grow. I’ve added a section to this site where you can &lt;a href=&quot;http://jessecrow.com/100days&quot;&gt;follow along&lt;/a&gt; and see what I’m making. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/07/22/starting-100-days.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/07/22/starting-100-days.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ch-Ch-Ch-Ch-Changes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The past almost three months since I graduated from The Iron Yard have been full of change. So much so that I’ve neglected this blog. However, that also changes starting today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change can be scary and hard but also refreshing and inspiring. I’m a person of habit—I like having a schedule and knowing what to expect, so change can be hard for me in that regard. I’ve spent a lot of time focusing on adjusting to newness the past few months, and have a new routine established. I feel fulfilled and proud and grateful for all that’s happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changes include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Getting my first design job! A week after graduation, I started freelancing for &lt;a href=&quot;https://favordelivery.com/&quot;&gt;Favor&lt;/a&gt;. In less than a month, I was on the team full time. I work very closely with the other designer on the team and have learned a lot about print design in the process. I also am much more confident in my Illustrator and Photoshop abilities. I&#39;m currently working on their style guide and am very excited to get my hands dirty with code again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Redesigning my portfolio. My week 11-12 Iron Yard self did a great job of the first design, while simultaneously completing my &lt;a href=&quot;http://jessecrow.com/nps/&quot;&gt;final project&lt;/a&gt;, but I grew increasingly unhappy with the design. I was glad to take a step back, think more about the messages I want to convey, and have a site that I&#39;m very happy with. Of course, I&#39;m always open for feedback! If you have any, you can send it my way &lt;a href=&quot;http://jessecrow.com/contact.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enjoying all the things I was looking forward to while in school. Spend more quality time with my fella and dogs? Check. Start taking banjo lessons? Check. Find a type of working out I enjoy and stick with it? Check. Spend more time in the sun? Check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These changes have been good, y’all, and I am so excited about all that’s happened and what’s to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/07/05/on-change.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/07/05/on-change.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meeting My Design Hero</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was a great day because I got to meet my design hero, &lt;a href=&quot;http://draplin.com/&quot;&gt;Aaron Draplin&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love Draplin’s work because it’s bold and timeless. It’s something to aspire to. My work isn’t all #thicklines like Draplin’s, but I want to make things that won’t fade as trends change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With encouragement from a dear friend and a rush of adrenalin, I walked up to Draplin while he was setting up the merch booth before his talk, introduced myself, and asked him if he had any advice for new designers. Highlights include: don’t move to Portland, do work you love, and people are going to try to make design not fun—avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got to sit front row for his talk with my teacher, Sam. It was hilarious and inspiring and so good to hear, especially as a new designer. Highlights from the talk include: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;show the things you love&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;it takes work to make good design&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;document your process&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;think about how much time we throw away and invent your life with that time&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;you don&#39;t have to take the carrot&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;get out there and get dirty&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;there&#39;s beauty in restraint&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Illustrator won&#39;t teach you anything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all boils down to one thing: “work hard and love this shit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/draplin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;with my design hero, Aaron Draplin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/04/30/meeting-my-hero.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/04/30/meeting-my-hero.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Demo Day</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was Demo Day and the end of my Iron Yard experience. Demo Day (and being at The Iron Yard in general) went by in the blink of an eye and it all feels like a blur. I can’t believe it’s over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Demo Day was set up science fair style, meaning it was conversation based, not pitch based, which took a lot of the pressure off.  I was so excited to share my final project (which you can find &lt;a href=&quot;http://jessecrow.com/projects/nationalparks.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) and talk about all I learned. I’m also very thankful to have a supportive fella, friends, and former co-workers who all came by to see my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about my final projects with others and seeing it in the wild was such a rewarding experience. It’s my capstone project that I’ve worked on for 14-16 hours a day for almost two weeks, that I’ve poured my heart into, that is an extension of me and everything I know as a designer and developer. I’m proud of the work I’ve done and all that I’ve learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Demo Day wrapped up, my cohort, our plus ones, and the teachers and staff went out to eat pizza and drink beer (treat yo’self) and then I went to see Sleater-Kinney with one of my dear friends and classmates. I don’t know what’s going to happen next, but I’m so excited for what’s to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/demoday.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;my booth setup at demo day&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/04/18/demo-day.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/04/18/demo-day.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Designing For Myself</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the midst of final projects, our class also worked on our personal logos and business cards. Designing something for myself is one of the most challenging things I’ve done so far in this class. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve put so much additional (and probably unnecessary) pressure on myself for my logo to be perfect. Not just design wise, but I’ve also felt like it has to be the perfect representation of myself. This, coupled with just turning twenty-five a couple weeks ago, has led me to feel like I’m in the thick of a quarter life crisis. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by asking family, friends, and Sam what five words and a color they associate with me to get an idea as to how others perceive me. Then our class doing a timed logo challenge like we did earlier in the cohort. From there, I sketched and iterated ideas, brought them into Illustrator, and iterated and iterated and iterated and fussed with pen tool points until I was satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My two main concepts were a bird and a mason jar. I ultimately decided to go with the mason jar because it has more depth and goes past the obvious (my last name is Crow, afterall). We got our business cards today and I’m over the moon with how they turned out and still can’t believe I’m getting into a world where I get to have business cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/personal-logos-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mason jar and bird logo iterations&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/personal-logos-v2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mason jar and bird logo iterations&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/bizcards.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;business cards&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/04/10/personal-logo-design.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/04/10/personal-logo-design.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting Final Projects</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Y’all, somehow the time has flown by and I’m starting my final project. This is not a drill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m feeling excited and inspired and a little overwhelmed about just how much work I have to get done in the next two weeks. I know I’m capable and armed with a fantastic schedule to stick with, but sometimes the size and importance of this project gets the best of me. Mostly I’m trying to shush the thoughts of “you only have ___ days left here” that have become more frequent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my final project, I’m going to redesign the home page of the National Park Service website and four pages from Great Smoky Mountains National Park’s website. So far I’ve done my research, created a word list, done brand/reputation, competitor, and SWOT analyses, considered the audience, come up with a list of potential concepts, and done sketches based on the strongest three concepts. Seems like a lot (and it is), but it’s only a small drop compared to what’s to come. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just need to keep in mind this mantra from Leslie Knope:
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/doit.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Inspirational Leslie Knope gif&quot; class=&quot;blog-gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/04/01/starting-final-projects.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.jessecrow.com/blog/2015/04/01/starting-final-projects.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
