<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jesse Crow</title>
    <description>Portfolio site for Austin-based designer, Jesse Crow.
</description>
    <link>http://crowjm.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://crowjm.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 17:41:30 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 17:41:30 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Basic Responsive Codepens</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Basic Responsive Codepens&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had our first Responsive Web Design (RWD) lecture on Friday. RWD means designing for all sorts of devices and screens. RWD means being inclusive and inclusiveness is my jam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, we had a few homework assignments to get used to RWD where we had to use percentages, media queries, and breakpoints. RWD is oddly comforting to me and makes me feel like I have more control over my code and therefore more control over the user’s experience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the Codepens I created with this weekend’s homework. If you click on the “Edit on Codepen” link in the upper right hand of each, they’ll open in a new tab and you’ll be able to resize the browser window to see all of their responsive glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;12329&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;raJqOP&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;crowjm&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/crowjm/pen/raJqOP/&quot;&gt;Responsive #1&lt;/a&gt; by Jesse Crow (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/crowjm&quot;&gt;@crowjm&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;12329&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;emVPzx&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;crowjm&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/crowjm/pen/emVPzx/&quot;&gt;Responsive #1&lt;/a&gt; by Jesse Crow (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/crowjm&quot;&gt;@crowjm&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;12329&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;ogEazj&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;crowjm&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/crowjm/pen/ogEazj/&quot;&gt;Responsive #1&lt;/a&gt; by Jesse Crow (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/crowjm&quot;&gt;@crowjm&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;12329&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;GgQYNW&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;crowjm&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/crowjm/pen/GgQYNW/&quot;&gt;Responsive #2&lt;/a&gt; by Jesse Crow (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/crowjm&quot;&gt;@crowjm&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://crowjm.github.io/2015/02/15/basic-responsive-codepens.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://crowjm.github.io/2015/02/15/basic-responsive-codepens.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sketches and Perfectionism</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;sketches-and-perfectionism&quot;&gt;Sketches and Perfectionism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first website sketching assignment sent me into a state of panic. I had to fight my inner perfectionist and accept having what I considered major flaws in my work (and consequently share work I wasn’t proud of).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were assigned ten websites that we had to sketch on a grid. And we had to use pen. PEN. I knew I would make mistakes and there would be nothing I could do to correct them and that’s when the panic began. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My instructor, Sam, talked about how sketches don’t have to be perfect, how they shouldn’t be perfect. They’re an important first step in the design process and they should be done quickly to get ideas down on the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sounded great until I started drawing crooked lines and divs in the wrong place. Even though I knew my sketches shouldn’t be perfect, I put pressure on myself to make them so. I felt like they couldn’t be used because they had mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to share our worst sketch the next day in class. I was terrified at first, but then I realized we all had mistakes. Lines weren’t straight, proportions were off, etc. What I had built up to be horrendous mistakes &lt;em&gt;weren’t mistakes at all&lt;/em&gt;. The layouts of the sites were still conveyed and we could understand what the others had sketched. And that’s the whole point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/first-sketches.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;A couple of my first sketches.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://crowjm.github.io/2015/02/12/sketches-and-perfectionism.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://crowjm.github.io/2015/02/12/sketches-and-perfectionism.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On Perseverance</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-perseverance&quot;&gt;On Perseverance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attending The Iron Yard is one of the most demanding, challenging, inspiring, and rewarding experiences I’ve ever had. I’m just over two weeks in and I’m amazed by how much I’ve learned, and how much more I’ll learn in the next two and a half months. The days can be long and the assignments push the limits of what I know. It’s all worth it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I quickly realized is that perseverance is key to getting the most out of this experience. Giving up on a hard problem or concept is not an option. New material gets introduced every day and builds on what we’ve already learned—to say class moves quickly is an understatement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to dig deep. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dig deep into the material. I can’t just read the material, I have to make sure I understand it. Sometimes it clicks right away and sometimes I have to explore other reliable resources or make a list of questions for class the next day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dig deep into the code. If something isn’t working, I have to take a break so that I can look at my code with a fresh set of eyes (for me, this means closing my computer and taking a walk). Did I forget a semicolon at the end of a CSS declaration? Did I forget that inline-block elements are weird and include any white space from HTML? Did I link to my Sass file instead of my CSS file?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I have to dig deep into myself. I know I can do this. I know that I know more than I think I do. Keeping this at the forefront can be difficult at times, but having a self-defeating attitude creates a doomsday spiral no one wants to go down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing about The Iron Yard is that no one has to go it alone. If I’m stumped, I have plenty of people around me who I can ask for help, who can be a sounding board, and who can point me in the right direction. When I figure out a challenging concept, I have people to high five. Persevering is a lot easier with a supportive community, and I’m thankful to be part of this one. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://crowjm.github.io/2015/02/11/on-perseverance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://crowjm.github.io/2015/02/11/on-perseverance.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Web Design?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-web-design&quot;&gt;Why Web Design?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I moved to Austin in March 2014 in search of new opportunities. I worked in retail, office management, and social media marketing before and couldn’t see myself making a career in any of those fields. I was very lost in terms of job direction and itching to find something I enjoy doing that I could turn into a career.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter web design.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started doing some online tutorials to get my feet wet. I was hooked after the first one. I was thrilled to use my brain again in a way I hadn’t since college, learn new and relevant skills, and think critically and creatively. And one day it dawned on me: &lt;em&gt;web design is related to my college degree; I CAN USE MY DEGREE IN THE REAL WORLD!&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I graduated from Millsaps College with a B.A. in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.millsaps.edu/academic_departments/department_of_communications.php&quot;&gt;Communication Studies&lt;/a&gt;. With everything I studied, I kept the media triangle (the consumer, the producer, and the text/product—and their relationship) in mind. I think my academic background will play a part in my process and what I create, and I’m excited to take a step back and analyze what I make from a Communication Studies perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Communication Studies tie in became very apparent with an article we read early in the second week of class. In the forward to &lt;a href=&quot;http://practicaltypography.com/foreword.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Practical Typography&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Erik Spiek­er­mann writes, “If you fail to consider the effect of your message on the recipient, you may inadvertently communicate that you do not care how your message may be received.” Effect, message, recipient, received—these words brought me right back to college lectures. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web design is more than just making things look pretty. You have to think critically and creatively and solve problems while building your site. You also have to consider the messages of your site. I’m excited to do all of these things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://crowjm.github.io/2015/02/10/why-web-design.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://crowjm.github.io/2015/02/10/why-web-design.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
